Guide to the Stanford University, Office of the Dean of Student Affairs, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Additional Records, 1974-1978; Accession ARCH-1984-058
  - Escondido Village, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Freshman facts, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Presidential Commission on university budget priorities, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Residential education - correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Residential education, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Additional Records, 1966-1991; Accession ARCH-1991-124
  - Board of Trustees
    - Background information, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Background information, 1971-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Committee on investment responsibility, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Career planning
    - Career planning and placement center, 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Career planning and placement center, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Career planning and placement center, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Committees
    - Contemporary entertainment evaluation, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Health and safety, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Parking and transportation, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Personal safety (DOSA committee), Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Student services and affairs, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Fire department, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Housing center (off campus study), Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Law School student center, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Energy crisis, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Residential Education
    - Eating clubs, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Florence Moore Hall, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - General/Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Orientation, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Orientation - Parents' responses, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Orientation - Parents' newsletter, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Resident fellows, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Room and board rates, Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Row: French house, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Row: New additions, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Row: Story house fire, Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Student Affairs
    - Admin. Services: Annual report miscellaneous information, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Admin. Services: Organization charts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Admin. Services: Personnel, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Admin. Services: Reorganization, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Budget, 1971-1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Budget, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Budget, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Budget, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Budget, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Budget, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Budget, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Budget, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Budget, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Budget, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Budget, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Budget, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Budget, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Budget letter, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Budget letter, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Budget three year plan, 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - College experiences study: Stanford, probably 1988 December (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - College experiences study, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - College experiences study, 1989 January (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Colloquium, Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Colloquium correspondence, Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Consortium: COHFE, Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Dean's Group, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Dinners, Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Executive committee (Unit heads), 1972-1979 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Executive committee, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Executive committee, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Executive committee, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Executive committee, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Executive committee, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Executive committee, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Executive committee, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Executive committee, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Executive committee, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Executive committee, 1990 June-1991 August (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - PAC-10, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Privacy: Alumni records, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Retreat, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Retreat, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Retreat, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Retreat, 1978, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Retreat, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Retreat, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Retreat, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Retreat, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Retreat, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Retreat, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Retreat (Non-exempt), Undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Selective service, Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Student affairs council, Undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Student consulting report, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Student counseling office, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Student support services task force II, Undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - University Departments
    - Cohort interviews (Jr. year), Undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Cohort interviews (Sr. year), Undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Cohort study retreat, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Cohort study retreat, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Cohort study, Undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Undergrad officers meeting January, Undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - SWOPSI/SCIRE, Undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Additional Records, 1973-1983; Accession ARCH-1991-169
  - Career planning and placement, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Legal counseling office, 1973-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes of budget priorities review meetings, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - A study of program and budget priorities of the office of the Dean of Student Affairs, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Additional Records, 1954-1975; Accession ARCH-1993-117
  - Attrition studies, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Reports on freshmen attrition, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Report on minority affairs, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Survey of commuting students at Stanford, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Criteria for Negro admissions to Stanford, 1967 March (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Report on the 1970 Task Force Summer Orientation program, 1970 November 4 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Three reports, 1962-1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Sub-Committee on Special Constituencies, 1967; Predictive Validity of SAT Scores and High School GPA for Black Students at Stanford, 1971; Factors Influencing Student Participation in Classroom Discussion, 1962.
  - Two reports, 1972 and undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Performance of Stanford Seniors on the Graduate Record Examinations, 1972; Report Concerning the Dean's List of Honor Students, undated.
  - History of Western Civilization questionnaires, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Four items, 1965-1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Behavior Modification of Study Habits of "Educationally-Disadvantaged" Students, 1966; three reports on academic behavior of students, 1965-1971.
  - Three reprints from studies done on Stanford students, 1954-1974 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    A Follow-up after Three Years of Clients Counseled by Two Methods, 1954; A Scale to Measure Teacher-Student Interaction, 1968; Patterns of Adaptation among Black Students at a Predominantly White University, 1974.
  - Four items, 1962-1968 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Two items on a demonstration house, 1968; Further Thoughts Regarding the Appraisal and Encouragement of Academic Performance, 1962; Proceedings of the Conference of Student Personnel Officers, 1962.
  - Two papers, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Student Reactions to Their Undergraduate Experience, 1966; Identifying Alienation in the College Student: A Validation Study, 1966.
  - Four items, 1961-1967 and undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Students and the Curriculum: The Open, the Straight, and the Narrow; Project: Encounter, 1967; Some Comments Regarding the Aptitudes, Aspirations, and Education of Stanford Undergraduates, 1961; The Control of Student Conduct.
  - A psychological classification scheme for vocations and major fields, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Reports from study on Western Civilization course, academic year reports, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Four items, 1957 and undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Some Impressions Regarding Student Needs at Stanford, June 1957; Questionnaire re: concerns of Stanford students; Description of Personality Scale Changes from Freshman to Senior Year; Ten Subscales Used in Analysis of the University Residence Environment Scale.
  - Four items, 1957-1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Stanford Community as Seen by Students, 1967 December; Preliminary Report on an Experiment in Group Counseling for Foreign Students, 1957 June; unnamed report on undergraduate education; memo re: study of 21 black freshmen at Stanford University, 1970.
  - Manual of Freshman Class Profiles, College Entrance Examination Board, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Manual of Freshman Class Profiles, College Entrance Examination Board, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Manual of Freshman Class Profiles, College Entrance Examination Board, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Manual of Freshman Class Profiles, College Entrance Examination Board, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Additional Records, 1971-1984; Accession ARCH-1993-121
  - Binder, 1971-1984 (Box 1)
    Binder contains the following items: Report of the Ad Hoc Committee on Residential Education, 1971 April; Study of Residential Life: a Summary Guide; New Undergraduate Residences at Stanford: A Report to the Board of Trustees, 1979 November; Residential Education Self-Study Report, 1980 November; Residential Education Self-Study: Discussion in the Committee on Undergraduate Studies, 1980 November; Furthering the Goal of Education in Stanford Undergraduate Residences, 1983 October; Report of the Committee on Undergraduate Studies on Issues of Residential Education at Stanford, 1984 May; Annual Report of the Committee of Undergraduate Studies, 1983-1984, 1984 October; Report of the Subcommittee on Residential Education and Advising, 1983-1984, 1984 November; Stanford University Bulletin: Information.
- Additional Records, 1966-1996; Accession ARCH-2007-212
  - Task force to study fraternities and sororities: introductory materials, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Task force to study fraternities and sororities: subcommittees, circa 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Task force to study fraternities and sororities: glossary and questionnaire, circa 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Task force to study fraternities and sororities: background information (1), circa 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Task force to study fraternities and sororities: background information (2), circa 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Task force to study fraternities and sororities: introductory materials and miscellaneous, circa 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Task force to study fraternities and sororities: meeting minutes, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Task force to study fraternities and sororities: agenda, rosters, visits, circa 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Task force to study fraternities and sororities: correspondence (1), circa 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Task force to study fraternities and sororities: correspondence (2), circa 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Interviews - Stanford fraternities and sororities, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Task force to study fraternities and sororities: intro, calendars, rosters, circa 1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Task force to study fraternities and sororities: minutes, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Task force to study fraternities and sororities: interviews, reports, visits, circa 1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Task force to study fraternities and sororities: questionnaire, circa 1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Task force to study fraternities and sororities: correspondence, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Task force to study fraternities and sororities: subcommittees, glossary, miscellany, background info, and computer disk, circa 1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Rush, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Rush, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Rush, 1977-1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Task force report, 1987 August (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Fraternal groups, Task force on fraternities and sororities, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Fraternity task force review, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - IFC historical: Fraternities/sororities, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - IFC historical: Fraternities/sororities, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - IFC historical: Fraternities/sororities, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Historical sorority information, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Fraternities and sororities: A policy review, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Fraternities and sororities at Stanford appendices, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Fraternities (memos, clippings, correspondence, etc.), 1972-1980 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Fraternity gifts and housing historical, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Fraternity news: Historical, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Fraternal minority issues, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Residential education. Fraternities: Draw exemption, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Residential education. Fraternities: Draw exemption, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Residential education. Alpha Phi Omega, 1977-1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Fraternity information - historical, Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Residential education. Fraternities, 1973-1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Residential education. Fraternities, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Residential education. Fraternities and sororities, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Residential education. Fraternities, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Residential education. Fraternities, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Residential education. Zeta Psi (1 of 2), 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Residential education. Zeta Psi (2 of 2), 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Residential education. Fraternities, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Residential education. Fraternities, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Residential education. Fraternities, 1976-1979 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Residential education. Fraternities. Delts, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Residential education. Fraternities. Delta Tau Delta, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Residential education. Fraternities. Delta Tau Delta, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Spring Draw, 1984-1989 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Residence evaluations, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Annual report: Residences, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Fraternities: News coverage, 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Fraternities: News coverage, 1978-1986 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Row information, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Greek leadership circle, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - All Greek Council: Constitution and judicial responsibilities, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - AGC minutes, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - AGC correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - All Greek news items, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Charter documents - fraternities, 1968-1982 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Fraternal affairs clippings, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Fraternal affairs clippings, 1988 April-June (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Fraternal affairs clippings, 1988 January-March (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Fraternal affairs clippings, 1987 July-November (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Fraternal affairs clippings, 1987 April-May (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Fraternal affairs clippings, 1987 January-March (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Fraternal affairs clippings, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Fraternal affairs clippings, 1986 October-November (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Fraternal affairs clippings, 1986 April-July (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Fraternal groups - Commission for COSS to study frats, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Fraternity - general, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Fraternity - general (incidents), 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Fraternal organization - information, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Fraternal organization - information (index cards), 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Task force report, Undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Task force report, Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Fraternities and sororities at Stanford - appendices, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Fraternal groups. Fraternity/sorority history, 1966-1984 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Fraternity task report - draft, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Fraternity task report - draft and response, Undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Fraternity task report - response from J.M. Pisano, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Fraternity task report - recommendations, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Fraternity task report - miscellaneous, Undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Fraternity task report (general information), Undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Fraternity task report, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Fraternity task reports, 1983-1988 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Study of fraternities at Stanford - interviews, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Greek task force - charge and emails, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Fraternal affairs - task force response, 1984-1989 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Fraternity task force review report, Undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - University recognition (sample letters), Undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Fraternity task force - reports and memos, 1976-1983 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Greek task force, 1986-1996 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Delta Upsilon suspension (1 of 2), 1986 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Delta Upsilon suspension (2 of 2), 1986 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Residential education. Delta Tau Delta incident., 1976 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Domestic partners - correspondence regarding, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Additional Records (2015-037), 1949-2002; 1 box(es) (Box 1)
  - Student housing, 1949-1996
    - Escondido Village -- includes photographs
    - Crothers Memorial
  - Annual Reports, 1995-2002
  - Graduate Student Association, 1977-1983